Olawole Ogunfunminiyi frankfurtmacmoses@gmail.com +1(832) 8150073



PROFILE / SUMMARY

Frankfurt is an experience and a business minded data analyst and oracle database developer; able to deliver valuable insights via data analytics and advance data driving methods, willing to experiment with custom algorithms and declarative rich user interface tools.

EXPERTISE

- Data mugging / cleaning and Descriptive
 Analysis with R tidyverse and other R packages
- Big Data Queries and Interpretation with Hive
- Machine Learning Algorithms with R and Python – sklearn, pandas, numpy and R caret package
- Reproducible Research and Report Generation with R
- Data visualization with R ggplot2 and python ggplot implementation

- Data Driving Application with Oracle Apex
- Oracle Weblogic and Glassfish server
- Object Oriented Design & Programming (Java and Python)
- Extensive knowledge of Linux operating system commands and scripting
- Tableau, Power BI, OBIEE, Oracle Report and other such reporting applications
- Communication and other leadership skills

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Application Developer/Data Analyst

Osun State Government/Word Bank, Nigeria

April 2014 – Till Date (Remote)

- Customized the default oracle P-Track (oracle apex) demo application for managing World Bank Youth Employment and Social Support Operations in Osun State.
- Build customized reporting module with oracle apex on ministry of finance payroll system
- Developed complex SQL query to pull data from multiple data sources to deal with policy Issues and conducted trends and patterns analysis to
 figure out root cause of policy Issues for the purpose of improving governance
- Developed intricate algorithms based on deep-dive statistical analysis and predictive data modeling that were used to deepen relationships, strengthen longevity and personalize interactions with citizen.
- Analyzed and processed complex data sets using advanced querying, visualization and analytics tools.
- Identified, measured and recommended improvement strategies for KPIs across all business areas.
- Responsible for parsing and merging datasets
- Furnished executive leadership team with insights, analytics, reports and recommendations enabling effective strategic planning across all
 ministry units, departments and parastatals.

Data Analyst

ChamsSwitch Limited (a subsidiary of Chams Plc)

February 2012 - March 2014

- Scrapped data from the web and collecting data from backend oracle database for business analysis.
- Performed ETL on telecom tariff files into oracle database for supporting sales department in resolving subscribers issues
- Built predictive and descriptive models for financial datasets to investigate underlying trends and patterns
- Participated in development all reporting dashboards, from discovery through implementation, and ensures it entire BI lifecycle: Data Modeling,
 Data Integration, Data Measurement, Data Validation, Data Visualization
- Conducted Hypothesis Test: T-test or Z-test for A/B test to guarantee statistically significant results for different user interfaces for the revenue collection platform - paycollect
- Conducted cluster analysis to identify patterns in income and revenue payment via the collection application
- Partner with stakeholders to apprehend data and reporting requirement to answer business problems

Worked with management to prioritize business and information need for the monthly executive meetings

Oracle PLSL Developer

MTN Nigeria

January 2009 - December 2011

- Involved in logical modeling and physical modeling of applications with oracle data modeler.
- Developed Stored Procedures, Functions, Packages and SQL Scripts using Oracle PL/SQL.
- Involved in creation of Conceptual Modeling covering all the business requirements.
- Loaded the data into database tables using SQL*loader from text and excel files.
- Developed data model, SQL Queries, SQL Query tuning process and Schemas.
- Created SQL*plus reports as per client's various needs, and developed business objects with PLSQL.
- Developed SQL scripts for Referential Integrity check, which checks validity of incoming data with master tables in database.
- Involved in updating procedures, functions, triggers, and packages for validation and loading of data into target table based on the current requirement.
- Involved in Design Development and Implementation of business Applications using Java/J2EE Technologies by creating "customized views" on top of oracle tables.

Java Business Component Developer

New Horizons Computer Learning Centre, Nigeria

June 2006 - November 2008

- Developing Java Business Components to connect with oracle database End
- Support Database Administrators in developing physical and logical database models
- Developed the middle layer for customized E-learning application.
- Participated in development of E-learning Application for Nigeria Bottling Company (NBC) and FCMB.
- Trained corporate organizations: Con-Oil Plc, Diamond, Bank First Bank Plc, EFCC etc in JAVA, XML, VB.NET, SQL SERVER, PL/SQL and ASP.NET

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATION:

Graduate Diploma Computer Science - Ladoke Akintola University of Technology, Nigeria

2017

Thesis Title: Comparative analysis of Pig and Hive

Master of Business Administration (MBA), Business School Netherlands

2015

Thesis Title: Improving Monitoring and Evaluation System Through Implementation of Big Data and Analytics In Osun State, Nigeria

BSC Soil Science - Obafemi Awolowo University - Nigeria

CERTIFICATIONS

	2008	Project N	√anagement	Professional,	PMP (ID:	1212004))
--	------	-----------	------------	---------------	-------	-----	----------	---

2007 Sun Certified Web Component Developer for the Java EE 1.4 Platform (SCWCD) Awarded by Sun Microsystems Incorporated 2006 Sun Certified Programmer for Java Platform (1.4) (SCJP) Awarded by Sun Microsystems Incorporated, Now Oracle Incorporation

2006 Oracle Certified Associate (OCA) Awarded by Oracle Incorporation

MOOC

John Hopkins University

Data Science Toolbox Getting and Cleaning Data R Programming Exploratory Data Analysis Statistical Inference Regression Model Reproducible Research

University of California, San Diego

Introduction to Big Data Analytics Hadoop Platform and Application Framework Introduction to Big Data